Charles Wu

UX Engineer

Summary

A versatile user-experience designer & developer. Adept in converting user needs into product requirements, with project analysis skills. Efficient at creating designs that translate into tangible results, through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

Experience

UX Engineer, Highline Beta

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

- Tested and deployed new features for internal and external projects, applying lean methodologies
- Explored and validated novel industry problems for new ventures
- Synthesized and validated solutions for the aforementioned problems

Sr UX Developer, CareerJSM

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

- Designed features, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for stakeholders, presenting new features
- Audited and implemented code for accessibility, responsiveness, and localization compatibility
- Conducted user testing and interviews iteratively for feature releases
- Mentored team members and led the company in best UX practices

UX Developer, Dive Networks

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

- Optimized content for web and TV mediums, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for target audiences
- Hosted company UX training sessions to enhance product usability and accessibility
- Developed an automation script to detect and flag visual differences

UX Developer, Crowd Curio

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

- Researched and prototyped a citizen-science based platform
- Improved user engagement by testing and optimizing different layouts and through added gamification elements
- Designed information architecture maps, wireframes, and website, created with HTML/CSS/JS

Education

Bachelors of Applied Science, University of Waterloo Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science 2015

Contact

charleswu.ca

hi@charleswu.ca

(+1) 647-767-6126

UX Skills

Product Strategy
User Research
Information Architecture Design
Interaction Design
Prototyping
Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

Dev Skills

HTML CSS (SCSS, BEM) JS (React, Ember) Python Git

Tools

Figma
Sketch
Invision
Axure
Illutsrator, Photoshop, After Effects
VSCode, Sublime, CLI

Hobbies & Interests

Rock climbing, bouldering
Photography
Video games
Volleyball
Cycling
Whiskey, Bourbon, Scotch